







AJAYBIR SINGH

Junior Developer

https://www.ajsingh.co.uk/



PROFILE

An experienced Web Developer and a BSc (Hons) Computer Science graduate, skilled in designing websites to meet clients' needs as well as achieving satisfactory outcomes for the organisation. A dedicated individual who is self-motivated and resilient towards their work responsibilities and has a proven record of successfully accomplishing projects for various organisations. Possesses excellent communication and interpersonal skills for meeting the designers, developers and project staff for progress updates. A flexible person, willing to keep learning to build a successful career as a Web Developer.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

BSc (Hons) Computer Science | De Montfort University 2020

- Achieved upper second classification (2:1) degree
- Having knowledge of coding different programming languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Php, MySQL
- Worked with databases using MySQL, and different operating systems such as Linux, Windows, MacOS
- Developed a wide range of different software applications during my degree, e.g., a web application with user login and booking system for final year project

A Levels

The City of Leicester College 2017

· A Level qualification in Business Studies, Psychology, and ICT

GCSE

The City of Leicester College 2015

7 GCSE's A-C including English and Math's

ASSOCIATED EXPERIENCE

Junior Web Developer | Zustech

February 2022 - Present

- Collaborate using tools such as MS Teams, Git and Jira to deliver software
- Work as a part of a SCRUM team using agile methodology to complete sprints for continuous integration
- Participate in sprint planning and sprint retrospectives meetings and discussions with all teams.
- Develop front-end of a learning management system using React JS based of wireframes of the UX team
- Fetch REST API endpoints using Axios provided by the back-end team for adding functionality to the website
- Provide insights on designs, the feasibility of solutions, and areas of improvement.
- Pair program with colleagues when coding, provide additional perspective and identify missed errors.
- Accelerated the time to load the pages by restructuring the code, removing redundant code, reducing application bugs and the duration for testing by reviewing the teams' code.
- Minified CSS, JavaScript, and HTML and ensured optimizing all images for the best quality and minimal memory.
- Meet projects requirements for the creation of new web pages by implementing front-end technical solutions that include filtering for and searching all the courses available on the website to be displayed at the course marketplace that lead to the courses overview to show the user in detail all the information on the course. All using API endpoints to fetch data and JavaScript methods for filtering.
- Collaborate with testers and utilize defect tracker to identify defects in the code and effectively resolve issues.
- Report defects related to non-working or non-responding endpoint and provide feedback on how to resolve the
- Restructured the API fetch call to resolve a non-working page after the endpoint change.
- Fixed styling issues on different kinds of pages and optimize for mobile responsiveness for a friendlier experience.

Junior Web Developer Intern | Future Care (UK) Ltd

February 2021 - July 2021

- · Drafted website wireframe designs and documentation based on client's requirements.
- · Developed and implemented required pages for the project about creating an interface for baby monitoring devices
- Implemented a login system for pages with restricted content
- Worked in a team to successfully produce the initial interface and members area for a service that will allow its users to monitor various elements such as temperature of a baby using the baby monitoring device.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Goods In | Lidl June 2021 - January 2022

- Took the role of leadership to support colleagues with quality control
- · Quantity checks to match against system order sheet and log any discrepancies

Customer Service | KFC

August 2018 - June 2021

- · Communicated effectively with customers and colleagues during busy periods.
- · Effectively assisted customers to resolve any complaints in a calm and professional manner

Brand Ambassador | 7 Miles Marketing

August 2017 - November 2017

- Liaised with a variety of customers to sell a variety of products to customers
- Provided excellent customer service by learning to interact with the community

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React.js, Php, C#, MySQL

✓ Web Skills: Responsive web design, Bootstrap

✓ Adobe Software: Photoshop, Illustrator

PERSONAL SKILLS

- ✓ Driving licence with a car
- ✓ Learned to English, Punjabi, Hindi and Cantonese
- ✓ A logical approach to problem solving
- ✓ The ability to work independently and in mixed teams
- ✓ Experience in sprint planning and retrospective
- ✓ Ability to manage a complex range of tasks and meet deadlines
- ✓ Good communication skills
- ✓ Ambitious to learn more as I'm currently learning Node.js and Express.js to be proficient in all tasks

REFERENCES

Available on request